RESUME

Profile Hilman Zuhfy

Probolinggo, Indonesia

Phone : 089696037834

Gmail : hilmanzhy@gmail.com

Github : https://github.com/hilmanzhy Blog : https://cornet2.blogspot.com

LinkedIn:

https://linkedin.com/in/hilmanzuhfy-224418171

Experienced System Engineer with 3 years history of working in the Telecommunication and IT Industry. Familiar

with project management & managed serviced time line. Currently held position System Engineer, with responsibility in project development Netsight in PT. Immobi Solusi Prima. Then as IoT & Software Developer as build and develop IoT Product such as Smartplug to electric efficiency in hotel, apartment & home.



Skills

Cloud Computing

- Amazon Web Service
- Google Cloud Platform

IaaS & IaaC

- Ansible, Terraform, Packer, Docker, RRD, Prometheus, Exporter
- VPC, EC2, Security, VM, Billing, Etc

Linux

- Command Line, Server, Cron, Bash Script, GUI, IPTables

Programming

- Python Language (Pandas, Flask, Numpy, GeoIP, SQLAlchemy, Etc.)
- C Language

Networking

- Mikrotik (Build & Config Server, Routing, Firewall, User Management, Bandwidth Management, Etc)
- Server (Build & Config Server, Routing, Firewall, User Management, Monitoring, Etc)
- Hardening & Secure OS
- LAN, WLAN, VPN, Proxy, Etc

Project Management

- Jira Software, Gitlab, Redmine

Database

- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MysQL

Embedded System & Internet of Things

- Microcontroller, Raspberry Pi, ESP8266, ESP32
- PCB Design (Eagle, Diptrace, PCB Express)
- Schematic (Eagle, Prometheus)
- HTTP, Websocket, MQTT, SocketIO, BLE, NFC, Etc

Hardware

- PCB Soldering, Wiring, Troubleshoot PCB, Etc

Experience

PT. Excellenta Solusi Teknologi / IT Engineer

Dec 2018 - Mei 2019, Depok, Indonesia

- Create a robotic learning curriculum for elementary junior high school students
- Research & Develop code from curriculum with Arduino and Raspberry PI
- Teach robotics training
- Create Mobile Application for UMKM

Freelancer

2019 - Now

- Temperature and humanity monitoring using Arduino and ESP 8266 via Firebase
- Home automation using Raspberry PI via Android Apps
- FarmBot (for watering plants, monitoring temperature, and humidity using Raspberry Pi)
- Monitoring data Agriculture using Raspberry PI via Web
- Alarm system security for housing using esp12e via Telegram Bot
- Data Logger with 32 I/O using Arduino Mega and Ethernet Shield to get data from sensors for Industry
- Smart Greenhouse to monitoring and control hydroponic using Raspberry and ESP32 chip
- Smart Egg Counter (hatching egg counting machine using industrial laser in cage)
- SmartPlayer (automatic touchscreen in capsule hotel rooms for light control, RFID and mp3 player at subsidiary PT. Nindya Karya)
- Aslis Smart System (automatic goat scales using Raspberry Pi with MQTT protocol)

PT. Vascomm Solusi Teknologi / IoT Software Developer

Sept 2019 - Sept 2020, Malang, Indonesia

- Research IoT Product for smart home systems
- Develop Nalaj Smartplug Product to control & monitoring energy with ESP12e using MQTT, SocketIO and API protocol and integrated in Mobile and Web Sitamoto

Github: https://github.com/hilmanzhy/singleccu_arduino

- Develop Hedeg smartplug to control 10 units & monitor energy with raspberry using MQTT,
 SocketIO and API protocol and integrated in Mobile and Web Sitamoto
 - Github: https://github.com/hilmanzhy/singleccu
- Develop smoke sensor to alarm notification with ESP12e using MQTT, SocketIO and API protocol and integrated in Mobile and Web Sitamoto
- Setting Secure system in hedeg smartplug with firewall & hardening OS

PT. Immobi Solusi Prima/ System Engineer

<u> Jan 2021 - Now, Jakarta, Indonesia</u>

Netview Project - Under Telkomsel

- Develop Python Code to get data monitoring Speedtest, Pingtest, Traceroute Test & API
 Test
- Setup & Configure Edge Raspberry PI to integrated data to server
- Setup & Configure EC2 AWS & GCP Cloud to integrated data to server
- Build flow & design infrastructure to handling data from EC2 & Edge
- Handling data & insert to database periodically
- Configure security system to secure own Instance & Edge
- Hardening Instance & Edge

Netsight Project - Under Telkom Indonesia

- Develop Python Code to get data monitoring Speedtest, Pingtest, Traceroute Test, API Test,
 Videostream Test
- Setup & Configure Edge Raspberry PI to integrated data to server
- Build EBS image with Packer Hashicorp
 - Github: https://github.com/hilmanzhy/packer-management
- Setup & Configure EC2 AWS & GCP Cloud to integrated data to server

- Build flow & design infrastructure to handling data from EC2 & Edge
- Build Automation System to deploy and edit config in EC2 & Edge with Ansible

Github: https://github.com/hilmanzhy/ansible-management

- Configure EC2 with Terraform to handle resource instance

Github: https://github.com/hilmanzhy/terraform-management

- Build Images & Containers services with Docker
- Build Monitoring System with EKS and Kibana dashboard to check resource and healtcheck systems

Github: https://github.com/hilmanzhy/kibana-dashboard

- Configure security system to secure own Instance & Edge
- Hardening Instance & Edge

Training & Certification

Cloud Practicioner Essentials AWS (Dicoding Indonesia)

Credential: https://www.dicoding.com/certificates/1RXYMQ79KXVM

Google Cloud basics (Dicoding Indonesia)

Credential: https://www.dicoding.com/certificates/1RXYMLYVMXVM

Become a Google Cloud Engineer (Dicoding Indonesia)

Credential: https://www.dicoding.com/certificates/N9ZO7NRRYZG5

RedHat Systems Administrator (IDN.ID Indonesia)

Credential:-

Basic Penetration Testing and Ethical Hacking (Talentaa Indonesia)

Credential:-

Education

Senior High School 2 Probolinggo

2012 - 2015, Probolinggo, East Java

Computer and Network Engineer

State Polytechnic of Jember

2015 - 2018, Jember, East Java

Computer Engineering

Awards

Participant and Team Lead ABU Indonesian Robot Contest

2016 - 2018

This contest has 2 robots collaborating to complete the mission as quickly as possible. 1 robot controlled by operator, 1 robot automatically. Microcontroller uses Arduino Due and many sensors. each year changes the theme of the ABU Asia Pacific

2nd Indonesian Robot Contest

<u>2016</u>

- Manual: Push automatic robots with EDF motor and climb poles to put propellers
- Automatic: Move to follow line sensors with wind power from manual robots and bring propellers

3th Indonesian Robot Contest

2018

- Manual: Take the ball and give it to the automatic robot
- Automatic: Throw the ball into 3 rings as high as 2 and 3 meters in several places